# **Justin Sutcliff**

justins210@gmail.com 301-300-2330

# **SUMMARY**

Aerospace engineer with passion for autonomous control systems and computer vision. Strong computer science skills with functional background in math and controls. Desire to expand AI/ML practical knowledge through applied research projects. Confident, self-directed learner heavily motivated in subjects aligned with personal interests.

## **EDUCATION**

# Purdue University - West Lafayette, IN

May 2019

• Bachelor of Science in Aerospace Engineering

#### **EMPLOYMENT**

# Textron Systems - Aerospace Engineer - Hunt Valley, MD

August 2021 to present

- Matured vision-based pose algorithms for use on Jetson embedded computing system for DARPA Sea
  Train unmanned surface vessel fleet
- Oversaw two intern team projects focused on expanding the autonomy lab's capabilities in the areas of vision-based perception and multi-agent collaborative autonomy
- Designed and simulated high level nonlinear model predictive control algorithms for landing VTOL systems on a target moving with 6 degrees of freedom
- Trained and deployed pose detection algorithm on Jetson Xavier system using PyTorch key point detection model and adapted PNP solver
- Performed hands on research with a state-of-the-art event camera. Characterized the sensor, examined direct application to common computer vision problems, and explored the integration of spiking neural networks on neuromorphic processors

# Bell - Stress Engineer / Flight Controls Software Engineer - Fort Worth, TX

August 2020 to August 2021

- Revised and developed high level requirements-based test procedures for updates to 429 low speed automated flight modes
- Performed initial analysis of and helped plan 412 tail rotor shaft fatigue testing in support of aircraft weight increase
- Developed a bird strike simulation model in LS-Dyna to test critical nose and windshield panels prior to physical testing in order to inform future certification efforts

#### Textron Systems - Controls Engineer - Hunt Valley, MD

August 2019 to August 2020

- Researched and characterized fiducial based computer vision algorithms, ultimately leading to award of DARPA Seatrain contract
- Worked with controls team to develop, test, and tune motion controller for Ripsaw and other tracked vehicle platforms
- Developed prototype embedded system to demonstrate a computer vision algorithm's ability to command the position of a UAS over a moving target
- Developed a mathematical plant model of tracked vehicles to allow controls team to better simulate and tune a body-rate motion controller
- Developed data processing tools to allow engineers to parse, display, and analyze test data faster and more accurately than previously possible
- Upgraded motor controller hardware on subscale test platform to incorporate torque-based control

# Spirit AeroSystems - Design Engineering Intern - Wichita, KS

Summer 2018

- Redesigned Boeing 737MAX over-wing intercostal and supporting structure to incorporate additional emergency equipment installation
- Examined viability of various masking techniques in order to streamline application process of paints and compounds during final stages of fuselage production

#### Aerial Agriculture - Research and Development - West Lafayette, IN

- Developed autonomous aerial vehicle platform for capturing multispectral images of vegetation to determine crop health
- Led product development of ground sensor system used to monitor high value crops

September 2015 to August 2016

# **CAMPUS INVOLVEMENT / LEADERSHIP**

#### **Purdue Engineering Presidents Council**

- Coordinate with other student organization leaders on campus to benefit the engineering community
- Functioned as liaison for feedback between students and the Dean of Engineering

#### **Purdue Drone Club**

- President: (2017 2018), Vice President: (2015 2016), Founding Member
- Hosted largest collegiate drone racing event in the nation two years in a row

# **CDRA – Collegiate Drone Racing Association**

- Founded nonprofit organization for the management of collegiate drone racing
- Designed organization website with ranking system used for yearly competition

# **Relevant Skills & Certifications**

- Secret-level clearance, active (August 2022–present)
- Part 107 remote pilot certificate
- 3D modeling and extensive 3D printing experience (CATIA V5/V6, NX, Solidworks, Fusion 360)
- PCB & circuit design, production, and assembly (KiCad, Autodesk Eagle)
- Software design experience (C, C++, C#, Python, Qt, Android Development, html, Linux)
- AI/ML experience (PyTorch, Tensorflow, Keras, TensorRT)
- Extensive MATLAB and Simulink experience

More information about coursework and major personal projects can be found at justinsutcliff.com

August 2017 to May 2019

August 2015 to May 2019

August 2017 to May 2019